JUAN LUIS AZULA PASTOR

-Home Address: Av. San Felipe 695, Opto 505, Jesús María, Lima, Perú -Mobile: 953-219-110 -Email: azula.juan@pucp.pe

PERSONAL PROFILE

Sociologist of PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF PERÚ (PUCP) and MSc in Social Science Research Methods of CARDIFF UNIVERSITY OF UNITED KINGDOM. I am a professional with initiative and perseverance. My interest topics are research methodology, applied statistics, organizational studies, sports sociology and sociology of technology. I am currently studying the Diploma of Specialization in Data Science for Social Sciences and Public Management in the Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP).

EDUCATION

MSc Social Science Research Methods (Sociology), Cardiff University.
 Training in Qualitative and Quantitative research methods.

2018-2019

- Licentiate in Sociology, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)
 Thesis Dissertation: Alcances y limitaciones de una experiencia de asociatividad. Acciones productivas y comerciales de pequeños productores algodoneros del Valle Pisco (Qualifying: Outstanding)
- Bachelor in Arts of Social Sciences, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)

2009-2013

Diploma in Applied Statistics, School of Engineering, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP)
 Training in sampling, design of questionnaires and multivariate statistical analysis techniques

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- Specialist, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP).

 Research promotion directorate, Vice Rectorate for Research. Results and Impact Evaluation Specialist.
- Teaching, National Institute of Statistics and Informatics
 Course: Research Methodology

2021-ongoing

- Analyst, Ministry of Education of Perú
 Directorate of School Management DIGE (2019-2021), Directorate of educational services in rural areas DISER (2016-2017) and the Directorate Support of Decentralized Education Management DAGED (2015-2016).
 I was responsible of generating evidence (data) for decision making.
- Teaching Assistant, Pontifical Catholic University of Perú (PUCP), School of Social Sciences

 Experience of teaching the following courses: Statistics for Social Sciences I and II, Data Processing Workshop (use of qualitative software such Atlas ti and quantitative as SPSS, Stata and R). I was in charge of the preparation and presentation of practical sessions once a week during each semester.
- Research Assistant, Research Center of Pacific University Perú (CIUP)

2014-2015

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant.

2013-2018

Ministry of Education, SASE Consultores, Pro Naturaleza, Center for Social, Economic, Political and Anthropological Research (CISEPA-PUCP), and others. I was responsible for information processing, creation of databases and information analysis.

Volunteer, Institute Bartolome de las Casas (IBC) – Perú.
 I worked with children in poverty situation, improving their academic skills in verbal and mathematical reasoning.

ACHIVEMENTS

- Responsible for giving the commencement address of Sociology School of Social Sciences 2013.
- Award of Good Practices in Educational Management in 2016 as part of the Directorate Support of Decentralized Education Management.

INTERESTS

I am interested in teaching at university level, quantitative and qualitative research. Also, I am great fan of sports like soccer, running and swimming. Nowadays, I seek to conduct research that consider sports activities as strategies of social inclusion and that contribute to the reduction of inequalities in society.

SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

PYTHON: Python Programming Language

R: The R Project for Statistical Computing – Intermediate

POWER BI: Power BI Desktop

SPSS: Statistical Package for Social Science – Advanced

CSPRO: Census and Survey Processing System – Intermediate **STATA:** Data Analysis and Statistical Software – Intermediate

ARCGIS: Georeferencing Software - Basic

REFERENCES

Phd. Robin Cavagnoud

Sociologist and demographer.

University Paris III, France. rcavagnoud@pucp.pe, 997068421

Phd. Hector Maletta

Economist.

Universidad de Buenos Aires (UBA), Argentina. hmaletta@gmail.com, 993151968